本∶臭虫,我们20分钟内在广场碰头.
Ben: Great Stinky, I'll meet you at the mall in twenty minutes.
我会在女人的内衣店里.还没有,我还没有得到老妈的许可,
I'll be in women's underwear.
但是别担心,很容易的.
No, I didn't get permission yet, but don't worry, it's no sweat.
迈克∶本,什么!穿女人的内衣!
Mike: Benny, excuse me!Women's underwear!
本∶什么嘛?
Ben: What's that for?
我又不是要穿,
I'm not gonna be wearing it,
我是说我会在女人内衣店里.
I'm just gonna be in the women's underwear department.
迈克∶这还差不多.
Mike: Oh, and that makes it OK!
本∶为什么你总是要打击我?
Ben: Why do you keep hitting me?
迈克,
Come on, Mike, me and Stinky are just going down to the mall to get our
我和臭虫只不过去广场的女人店打耳洞而已.
ears pierced in ladies' jewellery.
现在好多男人都打耳洞的!
Come on, a lot of guys get their ears pierced now!
迈克∶我知道,我只是提醒你一下.
Mike: I know, I just like smacking you around.
本∶住口,当我征得妈妈的同意后,我会变得很酷了.
Ben: Well, cut it out, I gotta stay cool for when I ask Mom for permission.
迈克∶妈妈!
Mike: Mom!Benny look,
那你还不如让她允许你穿女人的内衣呢.
you got a better shot at getting permission to wear women's underwear.
本∶你是这样想的!
Ben: You think so!
迈克:本,
Mike: Oh, Benny, the woman has no sense of humour.
她没有幽默感.我是说,
I mean, if you even ask her, she'll probably wash something out with soap...
她总是会打击你.
your mouth, if you're lucky.
本∶啦,啦,迈克,
Ben: Na, na, see Mike, you don't get it.
你不懂了吧.我本来是不需要跟你说这些的....
I don't wanna have to tell you this but...
但是,我还是告诉你吧,她跟我说我是她最喜欢的孩子.
well, I am the woman's favourite child, she told me so.
迈克∶拜托,她跟我们每个人都这样说的,
Mike: Oh, come on Benny, she tells every one of us that,
而我们却一直都把它当成一个大秘密..
and we're supposed to keep it some big secret
本∶噢不!
Ben: Oh no!
迈克∶我的建议是,你最好去找爸爸,让他允许你去打耳洞.
Mike: Look, I'll tell you my advice; ask Dad to get your ear pierced.
杰森∶他会说允许的.
Jason: And he'll say yes.
迈克∶哦,不是的.他会说,
Mike: Oh, not a shot.He'll say, son, is this really what you want?
儿子,这真的是你想要的吗?我想不是.
I think not.
本∶那有什么用呢?
Ben: Then, how is that better?
迈克∶因为,
Mike: Because, for a long time you guys can discuss it,
你们一定会讨论很久,在讨论的过程中,
and as you discuss it,
你可以提出其他别的一些要求,
you can bring up another couple of things that you want,
比如说皮夹克,
like a leather jacket,
带金属指头的长靴,爸爸不让你打耳朵会觉得很愧疚,
or boots with metal toes on them and then Dad will feel so bad about saying
所以他就会答应你其他的请求来减轻他的内疚.
no to the earrings that he'll cave on that.
本∶你这样试过?迈克,
Ben: You've actually tried this?Errm...
不管怎么样,还是谢谢你的建议,不过我还是要让我的魔力在妈妈身上奏效.
thanks for the advice, Mike, but I think I'll work my magic with Mom.
迈克∶我告诉你..
Mike: I'm telling you...
本∶哈罗,妈妈.
Ben: Hello, Mother.
麦琪∶嗨,本,迈克.
Maggie: Hi Benny, Mike.
本∶我和臭虫要去广场.
Ben: Ah, me and Stinky are going down to the mall.
麦琪∶好呀.
Maggie: Oh, fine.
本∶晚餐前回来.
Ben: Be back by dinner.
麦琪∶好,没问题.
Maggie: Fine.Oh, there it is.
本∶那我去打耳洞,行不行?
Ben: I'm gonna get my ear pierced, if that's OK?
麦琪∶行.
Maggie: Fine.
本∶迈克,看到了吧,
Ben: Well Mike, I guess we know she was lying to one of us when she
当她跟你说她最喜欢你的时候,那你是骗你呢.
said he was here favourite child.
麦琪∶打耳洞!
Maggie: Get your ear pearled!
本∶啊,是.
Ben: Ah, yeah.
麦琪∶本,做你的梦去吧.
Maggie: Right, Benny, in your dreams.
本∶妈妈,难道连商量的余地都没有吗?
Ben: Mom, can't we at least discuss this?
麦琪∶不能商量.
Maggie: No we can't.
我才不会让我的孩子为了赶时髦而毁损他的面容.
I am not going to have a child of mine disfiguring his face for fashion.
迈克∶我跟他说过了.
Mike: That's what I told him.
麦琪∶迈克,这个和你有关系吗?
Maggie: Mike, what do you have to do with this?
迈克∶我只想帮你的忙,如果你需要你想让他得到点教训,
Mike: Well, I'm just trying to help, Mom.
我很乐意为你效劳.
Look, if you need the kid smacked around a little bit, I'm happy to serve!
杰森∶大家好,我..
Jason: Hello everybody, I'm...
本∶爸爸,你能不能告诉妈妈,耳洞只不过一个可以长合起来的洞而已.
Ben: Dad, will you tell Mom, it's just a small hole that can grow shut.
杰森∶回来了.
Jason: ...home.
本∶嘿,其他男孩子都打了.
Ben: Hey, all the other guys are getting 'em.
麦琪∶我想如果其他男孩子穿女人内衣的话,
Maggie: And I suppose if all the other guys were wearing women's underwear
你也一定会的.
you would too.
迈克∶欢迎回家,爸爸.
Mike: Welcome home Pop.
杰森∶发生什么事了?
Jason: What's all this about?
迈克∶哦,本想去打耳洞.
Mike: Oh, the lad wants to get his lobe lanced.
杰森∶想什么?
Jason: His what?
本∶打耳洞.
Ben: My ear pearled.
如果我不带耳环的话,
I mean if I don't have an ear ring,
其他男孩子肯定会认为我是个胆小鬼...
all the other guys are gonna think I'm a sissy...
不要说这样会毁坏我的面貌.
and don't say I'd be disfiguring my face.
杰森∶好了,本,我会说那么可笑的话吗?
Jason: Oh, come on, Ben, would I say something ridiculous like that?
麦琪:杰森……
Maggie: Jason...
杰森∶亲爱的,给我点时间.本,你还没有和我讨论过呢.
Jason: One second honey.Ben, we haven't discussed this.
本∶太好了,让我们到厨房里去进行男人与男人的讨论.
Ben: Perfect, let's talk man to man in the kitchen.
麦琪∶杰森...
Maggie: Jason...
杰森∶不必担心宝贝儿,我会把他的念头消灭在萌芽状态阶段的..
Jason: Don't worry honey, I'll nip this in the bud...
麦琪∶我本来已经处理好了,你却要来横插一手...
Maggie: I mean to just jump in and take over like that, I was doing just fine.
杰森∶宝贝儿,对不起,我只是想呃...
Jason: Honey, I'm sorry, I was just err...
麦琪:我知道五年来一直是你来处理.但是现在我在家我要来处理孩子的问题.
Maggie: Well, I know what you were doing and for the last five years it
was your job to do it.
But I'm home now to deal with the kids' everyday problems and you're out
there working, so let me deal with the kids' everyday problems.
杰森∶好.
Jason: OK.
麦琪∶好了.
Maggie: OK.
杰森∶对不起,我不知道你有这么强烈的想法.
Jason: Sorry, I didn't know you felt so strongly about it.
麦琪∶我就有.
Maggie: Well, I do.
杰森∶行.
Jason: Fine.
麦琪∶行了.
Maggie: Fine.
杰森∶我不插手了.
Jason: I'm backing off.
麦琪∶好,谢谢.
Maggie: Good.Thanks.
迈克∶爸爸.
Mike: Dad...
杰森∶迈克,我知道你要说什么...
Jason: Mike, I know what you're gonna say...
迈克∶不,爸爸,我只是...
Mike: No, look, Dad, I was just...
杰森:算了,不是那样的,
Jason: Save it, it's not what it looks like, OK?I am not whipped.
不是么?
I am simply empathizing with your mother's position here;
我得支持你妈妈,
she wants me to step aside so she can do the parenting,
她让我不要管,我想这对于她的个人价值很重要.
and that's very important for her own self-worth.
迈克∶我只是想问你借一些钱.
Mike: I was just gonna ask you to borrow some money.
杰森∶我还以为你要跟我谈...哈哈.
Jason: I thought you wanted to talk...Ha ha.
迈克∶哈哈.
Mike: Ha ha.
杰森∶哈哈.
Jason: Ha ha.
迈克∶你借不借呢?
Mike: So what do you say?
杰森∶不借.
Jason: Na, na.
麦琪∶你这些想法都是从哪里学来的?从现在开始,
Maggie: Where do you get these ideas?
我要更加注意你的朋友,你看电视的习惯,
From now on I am gonna have to keep a much closer eye on your friends,
你的唱片,或者我还应该监听你的电话.
your TV viewing habits, your record albums,
本,你太自由了,
and maybe I'll even monitor a phone call or two.
现在,一切都停止了.
Ben, you've had too much freedom, and it's coming to a halt.
本∶爸爸马上就会进来吗?
Ben: Is Dad coming in soon?
麦琪∶不,本,现在由我来处理这件事情,不是你爸爸.
Maggie: No, Ben, I am handling this, not your father.
本∶好,夫人.
Ben: Yes, ma'am.And I was just telling Stinky how you're so understanding
亏我还跟臭虫说你是多么的通情达理,比爸爸好多了呢.
and your so much better than Dad is.
麦琪∶别想骗我.真的?
Maggie: Don't try to con me...Really?
不行,不行,
No, no, Ben, getting an earring is just not something I'm gonna allow
本,打耳洞这件事情我是绝对不会允许你做的.
you to do.
本∶但是你也打耳洞了,不是吗?
Ben: But you have your ears pearled, right?
麦琪∶是,我是打了.
Maggie: Yes, I do.
本∶开萝尔也打了,对吧?
Ben: And so does Carol, right?
麦琪∶是...
Maggie: Yes...
本∶所以,这是性别歧视.
Ben: So, this is sexism.
麦琪∶性别歧视!
Maggie: Sexism!
本∶是的,意味着这个决定....
Ben: Yeah, it means making a decision...
麦琪∶我明白它意味着什么,本.不错的努力,但是,啊啊!
Maggie: I know what it means, Ben.Nice try, but ah ah!
本:那我就去那个店里跟臭虫说一声我不打了行么.
Ben: Well can I at least go down to the mall and tell Stinky,
I'm not allowed.
麦琪∶臭虫已经在那里了!
Maggie: Stinky's already there!
本∶是的,他穿着女人的内衣在等着我.
Ben: Yeah, he's waiting for me in women's underwear.
麦琪∶好,你去告诉她.
Maggie: Fine, go tell him.
但是他是第一个你不能再和他玩的朋友.
But he'll be the first friend you won't be hanging around with any more.
本∶好.
Ben: Alright.
麦琪∶女人的内衣!本只是想打个耳洞而已,我想我应该偷笑才对.
Maggie: Women's underwear!I guess I should be glad he only wanted an earring.
杰森∶事情解决的怎么样了?
Jason: So, how'd it go?
麦琪∶很好.
Maggie: Fine, it went just fine.
杰森∶哦!不错,不错.
Jason: Oh, good, good.
麦琪∶你根本就知道整个事情的始末,
Maggie: And you know exactly how it went,
因为你就在楼梯上偷听.
because you were eavesdropping on the stair.
杰森∶偷听!哦!
Jason: Eavesdropping!Oh, Maggie, I have...
麦琪,也许我无意中是听到了一两句,
I might have accidentally overheard a sentence or two,
但是,那可不是偷听.
but I wouldn't say it was eavesdropping.
麦琪∶好吧,你说吧.
Maggie: Right!So, go ahead.
杰森∶说什么?
Jason: Go ahead, what?
麦琪∶告诉我,如果是你,
Maggie: Tell me how you would have handled it differently and far more
你会多么不同而有效的处理这件事.
effectively.
杰森∶既然你问了,那,
Jason: Well, since you asked, actually...
事实上...如果是我,我会和你采用完全相同的方式来处理.
hell, I would have handled it exactly the same as you did.
麦琪∶真的?
Maggie: Really?
杰森∶百分之百,几乎一样.
Jason: Absolutely...you know, pretty much.
麦琪∶几乎!
Maggie: Pretty much!
杰森∶我...可能会用一点点不同的方法.
Jason: Yeah.Well, I Mike:...might have...well just err...taken a slightly more different
approach
麦琪∶比如说?
Maggie: Like err...what?
杰森∶我认为...
Jason: Well, I think...
麦琪:不,杰森,
Maggie: No Jason, I don't even wanna hear it.
我不想听.
I am fully capable of dealing with things like this...
我觉得这样做很正确,工作以前我都是这样处理的.
as I did for years before I went to work and as I just did again.
杰森∶行.
Jason: Fine.
麦琪∶行了.
Maggie: Fine.
杰森∶我也感受到了你的需要,麦琪,
Jason: Being sensitive to your needs here, Maggie,
我知道你是想回到那种日复一日的家长教育方式,不需要我来帮你分担,
I recognize that you want to get back into that day-to-day parenting mode,
也不需要我放马后炮.虽然如此,
without me, over your shoulder, second guessing you all the time.
但是,不是你所做的每件事情都是对的.
Even though...you know, not all the things you do are...quite right.
麦琪∶我明白了.
Maggie: I see.
杰森∶我不是说他们错了,或是麦琪,只是...
Jason: I don't mean that they're wrong, either Maggie, just err...
麦琪∶啊哈.
Maggie: Ah ha.
杰森∶天啊,什么东西这么香!
Jason: Boy, something smells good around here!
麦琪∶哦!我也不知道是什么,因为我还没有开始准备晚餐呢.
Maggie: Oh!I can't imagine why, I haven't started dinner yet.
杰森∶我是说,要是你准备的话,肯定会更香.
Jason: No, that's my point; imagine how good it's gonna smell when you do.
麦琪∶啊,臭虫也不在家.啊哈,
Maggie: So, Stinky's not there either.
当本出现的时候,请让他回家,他早该在一个小时前就回来了.是的,
Aha, well when Ben shows up, please send him home,
谢谢你,苏利纨太太.不要说他.
he was due back an hour ago.Yes, thank you Mrs.Sullivan.Don't say it.
杰森∶不会把?本居然会没有按时回来吃晚餐,
Jason: What?I wasn't gonna say a word about how this is the first time
我真是都没有话说了,他可是一直都很准时的.
I can remember Ben being late for a meal.
迈克∶哦,妈妈,我饿死了,什么时候可以开饭呀?
Mike: Oh, Mom, I am starved, when's dinner?
麦琪:等本回来后,不过我要先检查他的耳朵有没有耳洞,
Maggie: After Ben gets home and I check his ears for holes,
不过最好别让我找到,否则他就不会好过.
which I better not find, or he will rue the day he was born.
迈克∶那我可以做点什么吗?我会等.嘿,爸爸,你在笑什么?
Mike: Well can I get something to go?I'll wait.Hey, Dad, why are you smiling?
杰森∶我哪有笑.我没有.是,我是在笑,不过那是笑我对你们源源不断的爱.
Jason: No, n...n...no I'm not smiling.I'm not.Yes, I'm smiling but it's
just the love that I have for all of you bubbling out
开萝尔∶不好意思,让大家久等了.
Carol: Hi!Sorry I'm late for dinner.
迈克∶你没有.妈妈和爸爸在闹矛盾呢.
Mike: You're not.Mom and Dad are fighting.
杰森和麦琪∶我们没有.
Jason and Maggie: We are not.
迈克∶看.
Mike: See.
麦琪∶开萝尔,坐下,等本一回来我们就吃饭.
Maggie: Carol, sit, we'll eat as soon as Ben gets back.
开萝尔∶从哪里回来?
Carol: Back from where?
迈克∶从不要穿耳洞.
Mike: From not getting an earring.
开萝尔:耳洞.爸爸,我觉得你已经制止了.
Carol: An earring.Well Dad, I assume you nipped that in the bud.
麦琪∶不,不是他,是我.不是你的爸爸,
Maggie: No, he didn't, I did.
是我,是这个经历了18个小时的痛苦后,生下你的我.
Not your father, me; the woman who bore you after eighteen hours of labour.
开萝尔∶对不起,我只是以为他又插手然后接管了呢,
Carol: Sorry, I just assumed that Dad jumped in and took over like he
因为他经常是这样的.
always does.
杰森∶我没有.
Jason: I certainly did not.
迈克∶爸爸退出了,这样妈妈才不会觉得她自己很失败.
Mike: Yeah, Dad is just backing off, so that Mom doesn't feel like a failure.
杰森∶什么?
Jason: What?
迈克∶嘿,我可没说,是你说的.
Mike: Hey, I didn't say it, you did.
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森:麦琪,你相信你的丈夫还是孩子?
Jason: Maggie, who are you gonna believe, your husband or this no account son?
麦琪∶继续,迈克.
Maggie: Go on, Mike.
迈克∶我知道的就是爸爸没有被打击到.
Mike: Well, err...I just...ow!!All I know is that Dad is not whipped.
开萝尔∶现在是时候让爸爸退居二线,
Carol: Well it's about time Dad backed off and let you handle some everyday
让妈妈都处理这些日常孩子们的问题了.
kid problems.
麦琪∶这才是我们可爱的孩子说的话.
Maggie: And this from our smartest child.
开萝尔∶如果当迈克在本现在这个年龄的时候,爸爸就退居二线,
Carol: Well if Dad had backed off when Mike was Ben's age,
让妈妈来管的话,也许他就不会变成今天这样让人讨厌的混球.
maybe he wouldn't have grown into the disgusting scuzz-ball he is today.
迈克:好吧,
Mike: Alright, look, until I was fourteen years old,
十四岁以前是妈妈在家里,
it was Mom who was at home with me,
所以我长成这个样子是女人的问题.
so if anyone's responsible for me being a scuzz-ball it's this woman.
开萝尔∶妈妈,也许你应该让爸爸来处理.
Carol: Errm...Mom, maybe you should let Dad handle this.
杰森∶这才是我们可爱的孩子说的话.
Jason: And this from our smartest child.
迈克∶那我们为什么不让我们可爱的孩子们说说他们对本要打耳洞这件事情的看法呢?
Mike: Why don't we just ask our most loveable child what they think of
this whole earring deal, OK?
开萝尔∶我已经告诉他们了.
Carol: I already told them.
迈克∶开萝尔,
Mike: I'm talking about me, Carol,
我说,我正好同意妈妈的做法,
and I just happen to agree with Mom to crush Ben like a little bug,
把本像小汽车一样的压碎.
like he is.
麦琪∶谢谢你,迈克.
Maggie: Why thank you, Mike.
迈克∶尤其是在开萝尔打了耳洞后,爸妈对她的态度.
Mike: Yeah, especially after what happened to Carol when she got her ears pearled.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
迈克∶你不记得了吗?
Mike: Oh, come on, don't you remember, Carol,
开萝尔,当他们耳洞的时候,
when they made that little hole,
整个百货公司都可以闻到那个味道.
the smell that came out cleared the whole department store.
本∶对不起,我回来晚了.
Ben: Hey everybody, sorry I'm late.
麦琪∶好本,检查时间.把你的耳朵给我看看.
Maggie: OK Ben, inspection time.Ears please.
本∶只是玩笑;妈妈.
Ben: Just a joke, Mom.
麦琪∶这件事情不好消,没有耳洞,好样的.
Maggie: Well, it wasn't funny.No holes, good.
本∶妈妈,我跟你说过我不会打耳洞,我就不会的.
Ben: Mom, I told you I wouldn't get an earring so I didn't.
麦琪∶乖儿子,快去洗个手,然后过来吃晚餐.
Maggie: Oh, good boy, go wash up for dinner.
本∶我弄了个纹身.
Ben: Instead, I got a tattoo.
麦琪∶纹身,纹身,你弄了个纹身!
Maggie: A tattoo, a tattoo, you got a tattoo!
本∶但是,我纹的是,妈妈.
Ben: But it says, mother.
麦琪∶我不管你纹什么,
Maggie: I don't care what it says, Ben.
本,
Do you realise for the rest of your life you'll be walking around with
难道你没意识到在你接下来的人生里你要一直把的名字带在你的胳膊上吗?
my name on your arm?
Ben: Well, we could add an S, and it would say, smother
麦琪∶不要诱导我,本.
Maggie: Oh.Don't tempt me, Ben.How could you do this to your body?
你怎么能这样对待你自己的身体呢?你知道吗?
Do you realise that when I was pregnant with you,
当我怀着你的时候,在9个月的时间里,我甚至连咖啡都不敢喝,
I walked around for nine months and didn't have a single cup of coffee
就是为了能让你的身体能完美无暇.可是现在,
so that your body would be perfect.
如果我知道会有这一天,怀你的时候我就应该去哥伦比亚直接从数上吃咖啡豆.
Now look at you, I could have gone to Columbia and sucked beans off trees.
本∶但是,你又没说不让我纹身.
Ben: You never said I couldn't get a tattoo.
麦琪∶好,现在就让我们来复习一下你不能做的事情.
Maggie: OK, fine, fine.Then let's go over all the other possibilities.
你不能用刀挖鼻子,
You not stick Knives up you nose, you may not gargle with razor blades,
你不能用刀片漱口,你不能喝从马桶里出来的水.
you may not drink water directly out of the toilet.
本∶妈妈,那你的意思是说,
Ben: So, Mom, are you saying that this tattoo is a lot worse than a little
我的纹身比打耳洞还要坏?
hole in my ear?
杰森:不是.
Jason: No.
麦琪∶我是说你以后都不准再穿短袖的衣服了.
Maggie: I'm saying it means no more short-sleeved shirts, ever.
迈克∶你为什么不上去直接把事情解决掉?
Mike: Why don't you go up there and straighten this thing out?
杰森∶不,不,那对你妈妈来说,不公平.
Jason: No, no, that wouldn't be fair to your mother.
麦琪∶本,我很生气.
Maggie: Ben, I am starting to get angry.
迈克∶你不觉得她这样对一些可以洗掉的纹身有点过头了吗?
Mike: Well, don't you think she's a little nuts over some tattoo that
just washes off.
杰森∶恩.
Jason: Yeah.
迈克∶也许她还不知道那个纹身是假的?
Mike: You think that maybe she doesn't know that it's a fake?
杰森∶嘿迈克,
Jason: Hey Mike, it's not my place to second guess what your mother does
我没有权利去告诉你妈妈她知道或不知道什么.
or doesn't know about these matters.
迈克∶爸爸,
Mike: Oh, come on Dad,
必须有人告诉她,本只过是想用假纹身来骗骗她,
somebody's got to tell her that Ben's just trying to freak her out with
让她认为打个耳洞是可以接受的.
this tattoo, so that an earring would be a relief.
杰森∶嘿,等等,你别去.
Jason: Hey, wait, wait, wait.Don't you go anywhere.
迈克∶爸爸,如果事情继续发展下去,妈妈会把本从窗口扔下去的.
Mike: Dad, if this keeps up, she's gonna throw him out the window!
杰森∶他还年轻,
Jason: He's young, he'll bounce.
可以弹跳起来.你妈妈她自己会把事情搞定的,
Come on, your mom's gotta figure this out on her own,
她需要证明自己.
she needs the validation.
迈克∶哦,我明白了,你这是在报复.
Mike: Yeah, but...Oh, I get it; you're just getting even.
杰森∶你说报复是什么意思?
Jason: Yeah.No, no, what do you mean getting even?
迈克∶你明知道妈妈想要处理这些,所以你就等在这里让她把事情搞砸,
Mike: You know, I mean, Mom wanted to handle this,
然后你就插手,
so you're just gonna let her blow it.
把事情搞定.
And then you're gonna jump in with the right answer.
我真傻,居然忘记了你是多么狡猾的男人.
You know sometimes I forget what a crafty dude you are.
杰森∶我不是.
Jason: I am not.
我本来是想处理本的事情的,如果我真的处理了,
OK, I was tempted to handle Ben, and if I was to have done it,
结果很可能就会不同了.
it would have turned out a lot different.
迈克∶什么结果?
Mike: Yeah?Like how?
杰森∶我会跟本说,如果你想打耳洞,
Jason: Well, like...I would have told Ben, you wanna get your ear pearled,
你就去吧,我不会反对.
get your ear pearled, that's OK with me.
迈克∶什么?
Mike: What?
杰森∶但是,在2个月内,
Jason: Yeah, but in like two months, like eight weeks go by,
比如8个星期后,
and Ben forgets about getting his ear pearled and then he moves on to
他肯定会忘记自己要打耳洞了,然后又去找一些别的愚蠢的事情.
another goofy thing he wants to do.
迈克∶如果他没有忘记呢?
Mike: Well, what if he doesn't forget?
杰森∶我们会给他一个选择.比如说,
Jason: We give him a choice.
你是要打耳洞还是要去学开车
You say, alright, you can get your ears pierced or take driver's ed.
迈克∶你是好样的.
Mike: Oh, you're good.
嘿,
Hey, wait a minute,
等等,你是在一次寒假的时候,
you made me choose driver's ed over spring break in Fort Lauderdale with
让我在学驾照与和埃迪和泊纳一起去打堡垒之间选择的.
Eddie and Boner.
杰森∶对,没错.
Jason: Yeah, yeah, yep, yep.
本:妈妈,给你看看我的纹身.
Ben: Come on Mom, let me show you something about my tattoo.
麦琪∶什么,它居然还可以跳舞?
Maggie: What, you can make it dance?
杰森∶我敢保证要是我来处理这件事情的话,他根本就用不着用一个假的纹身来戏弄你妈妈,
Jason: And I guarantee that if I were handling this thing right now,
但是,
he wouldn't up there running those mind games on your mother over this
她让我别插手,
phony tattoo...but she told me to butt out, and butt out I will...
所以我就不插手,直到她来请求我的帮助.
till she comes to me, begging for help.
迈克∶你还不是报复?
Mike: So you're not just getting even?
杰森∶你没听清楚我说的每一个字吗?
Jason: Haven't you heard a word I've said?
麦琪∶你就给我好好的待在房间里,直到我让你出来.
Maggie: And you'll stay in this room, young man, until I tell you to come out.
本∶妈妈,我要跟你说说我的纹身.
Ben: Mom, there's something you should know about my tattoo.
麦琪∶你跟我说过,罗西尼巴有一个.
Maggie: Roseanne Bar has one, you mention it.
开萝尔∶妈妈,我想你...
Carol: Mom, I just want you to...
麦琪∶开萝尔,拜托,我现在不需要任何的建议.
Maggie: Carol, please, I don't need any more advice right now, please.
开萝尔∶妈妈,我明白你的策略,
Carol: But Mom, I see your strategy here and I just want to tell you,
我只是想和你进行一次女人对女人的交谈,它一定会很棒的.
woman-to-woman, I think it's brilliant.
麦琪∶对不起.
Maggie: Pardon me.
开萝尔∶你一定要胜过爸爸.
Carol: You're gonna have the last laugh on Dad.
麦琪∶你的话是什么意思?
Maggie: What are you talking about?
开萝尔∶他和迈克在下面,正等着你搞砸呢.
Carol: He's down there with Mike, just waiting for you to blow it.
麦琪∶真的!
Maggie: He is!
开萝尔:他认为你相信本的纹身是真的太傻了.
Carol: He actually thinks that you're foolish enough to believe Ben's
tattoo is real.
麦琪∶他真的这样认为!
Maggie: He does.
开萝尔∶现在我明白了本继承了谁的轻信的性格.
Carol: Now I see where Ben gets his gullibility.
麦琪∶我...
Maggie: Yeah, well, I...
开萝尔∶那你打算下一步怎么办?
Carol: So, what's next?
麦琪∶我...
Maggie: Well, I...
开萝尔∶当然你应该让那只鼬鼠自作自受,
Carol: Of course, you let the weasel stew in his own juices until he admits
直到他承认他的真正的目的.
what he was trying to pull.
麦琪∶开萝尔,怎么可以把你爸爸叫鼬鼠呢?
Maggie: Carol, there is never an excuse for calling your father a weasel.
开萝尔∶我说的是本.
Carol: I meant Ben.
麦琪∶开萝尔,我明白了,我知道该怎么做了.
Maggie: Oh, well right, I can see Carol, that you're on to my plan.
开萝尔∶男人,谁希罕啊.
Carol: Men, who needs 'em.
麦琪∶本...
Maggie: Ben...
本∶妈妈,我有事情要跟你说...
Ben: Mom, there_s something I wanna tell you...
麦琪∶让我猜猜,你的纹身可以洗掉,对吧?
Maggie: Let me guess.That that tattoo washes off.
本∶你知道!
Ben: You knew that!
麦琪∶我当然知道.
Maggie: Of course I did.
本∶哇.
Ben: Wow.
麦琪∶你没想到我有这么厉害吧?
Maggie: Didn't you expect me to be that smart?
本∶没有.不像我对爸爸那样,
Ben: No.Well it's not like I'm dealing with Dad here...
不是说你很好对付....
Err, not that you're that dumb.Err...
妈妈,
Mom, the devil has taken control of my mouth and is making me say things
刚才魔鬼控制了我的嘴巴,让我说出了那些会让我后悔我的话.
I'll regret.
麦琪∶本,
Maggie: Admit it Ben,
你是不是以为因为你没有真的纹身,我会很开心,
you probably figured I'd be so glad you didn't get a real tattoo,
所以就会答应你去打耳洞.
I'd give in on the earring.
本∶恩,那是我的疯狂的,无意义的希望.我的方法奏效了吗?
Ben: Yeah, that was my pathetic, pointless hope.Did it work?
麦琪∶哦!本.
Maggie: Oh Ben.
杰森∶真是一个难忘的夜晚.
Jason: So, quite an evening.
麦琪∶恩.
Maggie: Mmm.
杰森∶耳环,纹身还有大喊大叫...天啦...
Jason: Yeah, earrings and tattoos and yelling...boy oh boy.
麦琪∶恩.
Maggie: Mmm.
杰森∶我想你和本之间一切都还顺利.
Jason: Yep, I guess everything went pretty well with you and Ben.
麦琪∶恩.
Maggie: Mmm.
杰森∶我肯定你一定做的很好.
Jason: Ya, well I'm sure you did just great.
麦琪∶你肯定吗?
Maggie: Are you?
杰森∶当然.
Jason: Of course I am.
麦琪∶这就是你做这些的原因.
Maggie: And that's why you're doing this.
杰森∶做什么?
Jason: Doing what?
麦琪∶追问我.
Maggie: Pumping me.
杰森∶我没有追问你.
Jason: I'm not pumping you.
麦琪:杰森,当我被追问的时候,我会很清楚的知道的.
Maggie:Jason, I happen to know when I'm being pumped.
杰森∶也许我对你和本之间发生的事情是有点好奇...
Jason: Well, err...maybe I'm a little bit curious about exactly what happened
between you and Ben.
麦琪∶为什么?你认为也许我根本处理不好.
Maggie: Why?You think maybe I didn't handle it well.
杰森∶是的.
Jason: Yes.
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森∶我是说,我很想知道,
Jason: I mean, yes, you handled it no, you handled it well...
不管你处理的好还是不好,我都想知道,你是怎么处理的?
that just I'm wondering, you know, exactly...you know, how?
麦琪∶杰森,难道说要你相信我能处理好这些小事情,
Maggie: Jason, is it too much to expect you to trust me to handle a little
都是奢望了吗?
thing like this?
杰森∶难道说我问问你说了些什么都是多余的了吗?
Jason: Well, is it too much for me to ask you exactly what was said?
麦琪∶我不是这个意思,只是你不断问我的原因让我觉得不爽.
Maggie: No, no, no, it's just the reason why you're asking.
我是说你那么急切的想要插手进来,告诉我该怎么做,
I mean you were dying to jump in to tell me what to do,
而现在,
and now you're dying to know what I did so that you can see that I
你有急切的想要知道我是怎么做的,而没有把事情搞砸.
didn't blow it.
杰森∶亲爱的,不是这样的.
Jason: Oh, come on honey, now that's not true.
这些年来,你在外面工作,
You know, it's just that all those years that you worked,
一直都是我在处理孩子们的事情,所以,现在我有点想念这些事情.
well this was my job, and I kind of miss it.
我对你有足够的信心,知道你会处理的很好的.
And I have every confidence that you just dealt with it great.
麦琪∶好,晚安.
Maggie: Good.Good night.
杰森∶但是我可以告诉你是怎么做的.
Jason: Bet I can even tell you what you did.
麦琪∶哦?
Maggie: Oh?
杰森∶是,你一定是因为纹身的诡计而惩罚了本,
Jason: Yep.I bet you punished Ben for that whole tattoo scam and then
你一定会责怪自己为什么不让他打耳洞,对吗?
you hung tough on your decision for no earring, right?
麦琪∶也许.
Maggie: Possibly.
杰森∶也许!
Jason: Possibly!
麦琪∶杰森,如果我愿意告诉你我的做法,
Maggie: Oh, Jason, if I tell you what I did, do you promise not to criticize,
你能不能保证不要批评,也不要放马后炮?
do you promise not to second guess?
杰森∶我保证.
Jason: Word of honour.
麦琪∶我没有为假纹身惩罚本.
Maggie: OK, I didn't punish Ben for his fake tattoo thing.
杰森∶哦!麦琪!!!
Jason: Oh, Maggie!!!
麦琪∶杰森,你保证过的.
Maggie: Jason, you promised.
我还告诉他,
And I told him that if it was really important to him that he could have
如果打耳洞对他来说真的很重要的话,那他可以去打.
his earring.
杰森∶不,麦琪.
Jason: No, come on Maggie.
麦琪∶杰森,我...
Maggie: Jason I...
杰森∶不是,如果是我,我也会这样处理的.
Jason: No, I was going like this.
迈克∶爸爸,爸爸,本受到了什么惩罚?
Mike: Oy Dad, Dad, what did Ben get?
杰森∶迈克,这些和你没有关系.
Jason: Mike, this doesn't concern you.
迈克∶快说,爸爸,妈妈怎么惩罚他?
Mike: Oh, come on, Dad, what did Mom give him?
1个月,2个月,没有零花钱?
One month, two months, no allowance?
杰森∶处罚的尺寸是我们想不到的.
Jason: Well let's just say that the size of the punishment was unexpected.
迈克∶哦,妈妈根本没有处罚他!
Mike: Oh, he got no punishment at all!
杰森∶你说对了.
Jason: You got it.
迈克∶不要告诉我他还被允许去打耳洞.
Mike: Oh, don't tell me he's gonna get his stinking earring.
杰森∶事实就是这样.
Jason: That's what I hear.
迈克∶你什么都没说?
Mike: And you're still not gonna say anything?
杰森:没有.
Jason: No.
迈克∶爸爸,你想我去帮你跟妈妈说句话吗?
Mike: Look, Dad, you want me to put in a word to Mom for you?
杰森∶迈克,这是你妈妈的要求,她做到了,她把事情解决了.
Jason: Mike, this was your mother's call; she made it, that settles it.
迈克∶那我得再考虑考虑到底要不要结婚.
Mike: Well, it sure gives me second thoughts about ever getting married.
杰森∶恩,是要好好考虑一下.
Jason: Good, go with that.
麦琪∶早上好.
Maggie: Morning.
迈克∶早安妈妈,不必担心,
Mike: Good morning Mom, oh and don't worry,
我们没有谈论你是怎么样把本的事情弄糟的.
we weren't talking about how you muffed the Ben deal.
哦,我的电话在响吗?
Ooh, is that my phone ringing?
麦琪∶我什么都没听到.
Maggie: I don't hear anything.
迈克∶为什么冒险?
Mike: Well, why take a chance?
麦琪∶要不要吃鸡蛋?
Maggie: Feel like some eggs?
杰森:好的,做你喜欢的.
Jason: Sure, and go ahead, cook 'em any way want to, I won't second guess you.
麦琪∶杰森,昨天晚上的事情还让你不开心了?
Maggie: Jason, are you still upset about last night?
杰森∶不敢,我哪有资格去干涉,我只是他爸爸而已.
Jason: Oh, nope, nope, nope, nope.Who am I to interfere?Only the boy's father.
麦琪∶亲爱的,我做的不公平吗?
Maggie: Honey, have I been unfair about this?
杰森∶是的.
Jason: Well, yes.
麦琪∶好吧,克莉丝,你要换一个尿片了.
Maggie: Ooh, Chrissy, you need a change.
杰森∶等你回来后,我们再继续讨论这个问题,
Jason: Then when you come back we are gonna talk about this because I
因为我觉得这关系到了自尊...
have had it up to here with this validation, self-worth...
本∶你好爸爸.
Ben: Hi Dad.
杰森∶本,耳洞的事情还没有做最后的决定.
Jason: Hi Ben, hey.Ben, this earring decision is far from final.
本∶真地?
Ben: Really?
杰森∶没错,你妈妈和我会再讨论一次,
Jason: Yes, your mother and I will discuss it, and I guarantee you,
我跟你保证,结果会大相径庭.
the ending will be far different.
本∶真的?
Ben: Really?Then I'm not grounded!
那我就不用考虑了!
Oh, this is great,
太好了,我要打电话告诉臭虫,
I gotta call Stinky and tell him I don't have to wait two months to get
我不用等2个月再去打耳洞了.
my ear pearled.
杰森∶什么?嘿,嘿,嘿!
Jason: What?Hey, hey, hey!
麦琪∶你要本现在就去打耳洞?
Maggie: You want Ben to get his ear pearled now?
杰森∶我不知道我跟他说了什么..等等,
Jason: Oh, I don't know what I told him Maggie...
是你跟他说让他现在去的?
Wait a minute, isn't that what you told him?
麦琪∶不是,我跟他说他必须等2个月,
Maggie: No, I told him he had to wait two months and then see if he
到时再看看他是否真的要去打.
really wanted it.
杰森∶你昨天晚上又没有跟我提过!
Jason: Well you didn't mention that last night!
麦琪∶哦,可能是因为你对我赞不绝口,所以我就忘记了.
Maggie: Well with all the clapping it must have slipped my mind.
开萝尔∶我听见阴险的人在说话了?爸爸放进了2美分,
Carol: Did, I hear the little rat-face right?
然后把整件事情都搞砸了.
Dad put his two Cents in and messed everything up.
杰森∶开萝尔,基本上...是.
Jason: Carol, basically...yes.
麦琪∶开萝尔,去告诉本我原来的惩罚仍然有效.
Maggie: Carol, go tell Ben that my original punishment still stands.
开萝尔∶非常乐意,如果他反抗的话,我会狠狠的揍他的.
Carol: Gladly, and if he resists, I'll slap him around.
杰森∶你在玩弄我.
Jason: You were playing with me.
麦琪∶是的.
Maggie: God help me, I was.
杰森∶为什么?
Jason: Why?
麦琪∶杰森,既然你已经出去工作了,
Maggie: Oh, Jason, it's important that you trust me,
所以你要相信我,相信我能处理好孩子们的事情.
I mean totally trust me to
deal with the kids now that you're gone during the day
杰森∶宝贝儿,我真的相信你.
Jason: Honey, I do trust you.
麦琪∶肯定,现在.
Maggie: Sure, now.
杰森∶但是,你这样做是一种卑鄙手段.
Jason: It was still a dirty trick.
麦琪∶谢谢.亲爱的,相信我,
Maggie: Thank you.Honey, believe me, I know what you're going through.
我明白你的处境.你以前是一天到晚都跟着他们,处理他们的事情,然后,
You were here with them all day every day and all of a sudden you're out
突然之间,你就到外面去工作了,你再也不能像以前那样来处理每个问题了.
there working and you're not here to deal with every problem.
杰森∶我也明白你的处境.
Jason: And I know what you're going through,
一到下午3点你就要开始被他们烦了,你的话成了唯一的道理,
three o' clock in the afternoon and all hellbreaks loose,
而你自己却都不是那么的肯定.
and yours is the only voice of reason, and you're not even sure about that.
麦琪∶这样看来,我们是相互了解的.
Maggie: So, we do understand each other.
杰森∶我们一直都是.
Jason: We always have.
我要指出的是,
You know that I could point out that the way you ended up handling Ben
你解决本的事情所采用的方法和我想要用的完全一样.
is exactly the way I would have done it.
麦琪∶你能,但是你不会,
Maggie: You could, but you won't, right? Jason: Right.
对吗?杰森∶是的,我可以指出父母共同来教育孩子才是真正的抚养孩子,
I could point out that two parents,
麦琪.我还可以指出凭着我在儿童抚养方面的培训和经验,
parenting as parents is what parenting is all about, Maggie.
对指导我们孩子的人生有着极大的价值.我甚至可以指出一切,
I could point out that with my training and experience with child-rearing,
但是,我不会说...那就是我为什么不说的原因.
it's a very valuable tool in guiding our kids on the guide of life.
00:21:52,900
I could point out all of that Maggie, but I won't...and that's why I won't.